{"name": "B05 2018-12", "questions": [{"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "1. Marine biologists collected a sample of 40 adult sea turtles from Hammerhead Bay and estimated the age, in whole years, of each turtle. The histogram below shows the frequency of sea turtles for each of the estimated age groups. What is the maximum possible number of sea turtles that could have had an estimated age of 45 years\uff1f", "choices": {"A": "1", "B": "5", "C": "9", "D": "10", "E": "40"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "2. The sum of the measures of the interior angles of a convex polygon with t sides is 180(t - 2) degrees. What is the sum of the measures of the interior angles of a convex polygon with 10 sides?", "choices": {"A": "900\u00b0", "B": "1,440\u00b0", "C": "1,798\u00b0", "D": "1,800\u00b0", "E": "2,160\u00b0"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "3. In the standard (x,y) coordinate plane, point A has coordinates (-8, -3). Point A is translated 8 units to the right and 3 units up, and that image is labeled A\u2019. What are the coordinates of A' ?", "choices": {"A": "(-16, -6)", "B": "(-11, -11)", "C": "(-8, -6)", "D": "(0, 0)", "E": "(16, 6)"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "4. For all nonzero values of x and y, which of the following expressions is equivalent to  ?", "choices": {"A": "-7x3y2 ", "B": "-7x4y4 ", "C": "-7x5y4 ", "D": "-24x3y2 ", "E": "-32x3y2 "}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "5. What is the volume, in cubic inches, of a right circular cone with radius 3 inches and height 6 inches?(Note: The volume of a right circular cone with radius r and height h is .)", "choices": {"A": "6\u03c0", "B": "12\u03c0", "C": "18\u03c0", "D": "27\u03c0", "E": "36\u03c0"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "6. The expression  is equivalent to:", "choices": {"A": "x10 ", "B": "x24  ", "C": "x4,096 ", "D": "6x2 ", "E": "6x3  "}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "7. Milo earns his regular pay of $12.00 per hour for up to 40 hours of work per week. For each hour over 40 hours of work per week. Milo earns times his regular pay. How much does Milo earn in a week in which he works 45 hours?", "choices": {"A": "$337.50", "B": "$540.00", "C": "$570.00", "D": " $607.50", "E": "$810.00"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "8. Which of the following matrices is equal to + ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": " ", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "9. Tomi has 6 pairs of shoes, 4 pairs of pants, and 6 shirts, which can be worn in any combination. He needs to choose a clothes combination to wear to the school dance. How many different combinations consisting of 1 of his 6 pairs of shoes, 1 of his 4 pairs of pants, and 1 of his 6 shirts are possible for Tomi to wear to the dance ?", "choices": {"A": "10", "B": "16", "C": "24", "D": "48", "E": "144"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "10. In the standard (x,y) coordinate plane below, the graph of the equation  y = -2(x +1 )2 + 8  intersects the x-axis at points ( -3,0) and (a,0) and has its vertex at point ( -1 , 8 ) . What i s the value of a ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "1", "C": "", "D": "2", "E": "3"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "11. What is the least common denominator of the fractions ,, and  ?", "choices": {"A": "112", "B": "336", "C": "504", "D": "2,688", "E": "8,064"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "12. In the standard (x,y) coordinate plane, what is the slope of the line through (-7,3) and (2,4) ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "13. A group of 60 students and 4 sponsors took a field trip to a local museum. For their first guided tour, students were given a choice of 1 of 3 art exhibits. Of the 60 students, chose Modern, chose American Folk, and  chose Western. Each student that expressed a choice chose exactly 1 exhibit. The remaining students expressed no choice. How many of the students expressed no choice?", "choices": {"A": "5", "B": "6", "C": "10", "D": "15", "E": "30"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "14. What is the greatest integer solution to  6x - 2 \u2264 11.2 ?", "choices": {"A": "-2", "B": "-1", "C": "1", "D": "2", "E": "3"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "15. Classics Online charges a onetime registration fee of $17.50 and sells classical music downloads for $0.70 per song. Ian has $50.00 that he will use to pay the registration fee and buy classical music from Classics Online. What is the maximum number of songs Ian can buy?", "choices": {"A": "25", "B": "32", "C": "35", "D": "46", "E": "53"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "16. The lengths of corresponding sides of 2 similar right triangles are in the ratio 2:9. The hypotenuse of the smaller triangle is 8 inches long. How many inches long is the hypotenuse of the larger triangle?", "choices": {"A": "4.5", "B": "11", "C": "15", "D": "18", "E": "36"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "17. The mean age of the 5 people in a room is 30 years. One of the 5 people, whose age is 50 years, leaves the room. What is the mean age of the 4 people remaining in the room?", "choices": {"A": "14", "B": "20", "C": "25", "D": "30", "E": "35"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "18. In the figure below, B lies on AC, E lies on DF,  AC II DF, \u25b3EBF is isosceles with  BE BF , and CBF measures 32\u00b0. What is the measure of BED?", "choices": {"A": "106\u00b0", "B": "116\u00b0", "C": "122\u00b0", "D": "132\u00b0", "E": "148\u00b0"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "19. If x = -1 and y = 2, what is the value of  x3 - 2x2y - 4xy2 + 8 ?", "choices": {"A": "-13", "B": "-5", "C": "19", "D": "23", "E": "27"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "20. A retailer is comparing the costs of buying 3 products from 1 of 2 companies. The cost of each product from both companies is shown in the table below.The retailer will buy 10 of Product 1, 12 of Product 2, and 5 of Product 3. How much more will it cost the retailer to purchase these products from Company A than to purchase these products from Company B ? ", "choices": {"A": "$ 0.25", "B": "$ 1.25", "C": "$ 2.25", "D": "$ 6.75", "E": "$ 12.25"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "21. Line \b is shown in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane below. Alicia drew line  p with a slope that is of the slope of line  and with a y-intercept that is 3 times the y-intercept of line . One of the following equations represents line  p. Which one ? ", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "22. One angle measure and 2 side lengths, in inches, are given in the right scalene triangle below. In terms of  a and  b, what is sin ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "23. Each side of square ABCD has a length of 50 cm. A certain rectangle whose area is equal to the area of ABCD has a width of 10cm. What is the length, in centimeters, of the rectangle?", "choices": {"A": "40", "B": "50", "C": "60", "D": "125", "E": "250"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "24. If  f(x) = 5x2 - 6x + 1  and  g(x) = x2 - 2 , which of the following expressions represents (fg)(x) ? ", "choices": {"A": " 6x2 - 6x - 1 ", "B": " 5x4 - 26x2 + 33", "C": "5x4 - 20x2 - 6x + 21", "D": "5x4 - 6x3 - 9x2 + 12x - 2", "E": "25x4 - 60x3 + 46x2 - 12x - 1"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "25. A bag contains 12 red marbles, 14 yellow marbles, and 8 green marbles. How many additional red marbles must be added to the 34 marbles already in the bag so that the probability of randomly drawing a red marble is ?", "choices": {"A": "16", "B": "21", "C": "29", "D": "34", "E": "44"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "26. Megan and Louisa are side-by-side (at point A in the figure shown below) when they begin to run at the same time clockwise (C) around a small circular track. Megan runs at a rate of 40 seconds per lap, while Louisa runs at a rate of 70 seconds per lap.Which of the following figures best represents Megan\u2019s and Louisa's locations 120 seconds after they begin to run?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "27. The statement  3x - (x + 6) + 8 = 2x + 14  is true for:", "choices": {"A": "x = 0 only.", "B": "x = 4 only.", "C": "x = 7 only.", "D": "all values of x.", "E": "no values of x."}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "28. The first 7 terms in an arithmetic sequence are listed below. What is the difference between the mean and the median of the 7 terms?, 1, , 2, , 3, ", "choices": {"A": "0", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "2", "E": "9"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "29. What is the product of the complex numbers ( -2i + 5) and (2i + 5) ?", "choices": {"A": "3", "B": "21", "C": "29", "D": "20i - 21", "E": "20i + 21"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "30. Which of the following expressions represents the sum of 3.8 \u00d7 105 and 6.4 \u00d7 104 in scientific notation?", "choices": {"A": "1.02 \u00d7 1010 ", "B": "4.44 \u00d7 104 ", "C": "4.44 \u00d7 105 ", "D": "1.02 \u00d7 1020 ", "E": "4.44 \u00d7 104 "}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "31. Lian has yards of ribbon she will use to make bows. She will use yard of ribbon to make each bow. After Lian has made all the bows possible with the ribbon, what length of ribbon, in yards, will NOT have been used to make bows?", "choices": {"A": "0", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "32. Use the following information to answer questions 32-34.Carl purchased a new car. The fuel economy window sticker on the new car contained the information shown below. In this figure, MPG is miles per gallon.32. Carl is planning a trip in his new car that will include 350 miles of highway driving. Using the average fuel cost per gallon given in the fuel economy window sticker, which of the following dollar amounts is closest to his total cost for fuel over the 350 miles of highway driving?", "choices": {"A": "\ud83d\udcb243.75", "B": "\ud83d\udcb251.85", "C": "\ud83d\udcb256.00", "D": "\ud83d\udcb263.64", "E": "\ud83d\udcb287.50"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "33. Use the following information to answer questions 32-34.Carl purchased a new car. The fuel economy window sticker on the new car contained the information shown below. In this figure, MPG is miles per gallon.33. The cost estimates are based on a certain number of miles driven per year. To the nearest 1,000 miles, what is this number?", "choices": {"A": " 13,000", "B": " 15,000", "C": " 16,000", "D": " 19,000", "E": "22,000"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "34. Use the following information to answer questions 32-34.Carl purchased a new car. The fuel economy window sticker on the new car contained the information shown below. In this figure, MPG is miles per gallon.34. Based on the annual fuel cost estimate for this car and the estimate for how much Carl will save in fuel costs over the next 5 years, what would be the expected annual fuel cost of an average new vehicle?", "choices": {"A": " \ud83d\udcb21,180", "B": " \ud83d\udcb22,950", "C": " \ud83d\udcb23,100", "D": "\ud83d\udcb23,500", "E": "\ud83d\udcb23,980"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "35. A certain race car has a maximum speed of 240 miles per hour. Which of the following is an expression for this maximum speed in feet per second?(Note: 1 mile = 5,280 feet)", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "36. A chemist needs 1 ounce of element X. The only way which the chemist can get element X is to buy compound Y, which contains 10% X. Compound Y costs $2.40 per pound (16 ounces). How much must the chemist pay in order to ensure that she receives 1 ounce of element X ?", "choices": {"A": "$ .15", "B": "$ .24", "C": "$1.50", "D": "$2.40", "E": "$3.84"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "37. Emi traveled to 3 locations during a workday. Emi remained at each location a whole number of hours. The graph below shows the relationship between time, in hours, into her workday and total distance, in kilometers, traveled. Which of the following values is closest to Emi\u2019s average speed, in kilometers per hour, for the parts of the workday when she was traveling?", "choices": {"A": "60", "B": "75", "C": "80", "D": "100", "E": "125"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "38. What are all and only the values of x that are NOT in the domain of the function  ?", "choices": {"A": "-8 and 6", "B": "-6 and 8", "C": "-2 and 7", "D": "-8, -7, 2, and 6", "E": "-6, -2, 7, and 8"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "39. A new band asked its audience to rate the band\u2019s performance on a scale from 1 (poor) through 5 (excellent). The table below gives the percentage of the audience that gave each of the ratings. To the nearest 0.1, what was the mean rating given by this audience?", "choices": {"A": "2.0", "B": "2.8", "C": "3.0", "D": "4.0", "E": "4.1"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "40. In \u25b3DEF, the length of DE is  cm, and the length of EF is 6 cm. If it can be determined, what is the length, in centimeters, of DF ?", "choices": {"A": "6", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": "Cannot be determined from the given information"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "41. Let  a and  b represent real numbers with the property 0\" style=\"font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &quot;PingFang SC&quot;, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, STHeiti, &quot;Microsoft Yahei&quot;, Tahoma, Simsun, sans-serif;\">. Which of the following statements about a and b CANNOT be true?", "choices": {"A": "a - b \uff1c 1", "B": "a - b = 1", "C": "a \uff1c 1 and b \uff1e 0", "D": "a \uff1c 1 and b = 0", "E": "a \uff1c 0 and b \uff1e 0"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "42. Juwan has 150 cm of wire. For a craft project, he uses all the wire to make 1 circle with a radius of 5 cm and 1 square. To the nearest 0.1 cm. what is the side length of the square?", "choices": {"A": "17.9", "B": "29.6", "C": "32.6", "D": "33.6", "E": "118.6"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "43. Use the following information to answer questions 43-46.A local recycling center pays customers for cans, bottles, and cardboard. After processing these items, the center then resells them to XYZ Inc. The recycling center\u2019s payments to customers and the resale prices paid by XYZ Inc. are given in the table below.43.  The closed box with no overlapping pieces whose dimensions are given below is made with cardboard that weighs 1 pound per square foot of the surface area of the box. Which of the following values is closest to the amount the recycling center will pay a customer for this box?", "choices": {"A": "$0.24", "B": "$0.36", "C": "$0.48", "D": "$0.52", "E": "$1.04"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "44. Use the following information to answer questions 43-46.A local recycling center pays customers for cans, bottles, and cardboard. After processing these items, the center then resells them to XYZ Inc. The recycling center\u2019s payments to customers and the resale prices paid by XYZ Inc. are given in the table below.44.\tThe cost of processing cans and bottles at the recycling center is $0.03 per can and $0.02 per bottle. After paying the processing cost and the payment to customers, what is the recycling center\u2019s pro\ufb01t on the resale of 200 cans and 300 bottles to XYZ Inc. ?", "choices": {"A": "$32.00", "B": "$40.00", "C": "$48.00", "D": "$84.00", "E": "$112.00"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "45. Use the following information to answer questions 43-46.A local recycling center pays customers for cans, bottles, and cardboard. After processing these items, the center then resells them to XYZ Inc. The recycling center\u2019s payments to customers and the resale prices paid by XYZ Inc. are given in the table below.45.\tTo the nearest 1%, the recycling center\u2019s payment to a customer for a bottle is what percent of the resale price of a bottle sold to XYZ Inc. ?", "choices": {"A": " 8%", "B": " 56%", "C": " 80%", "D": " 125%", "E": " 180%"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "46. Use the following information to answer questions 43-46.A local recycling center pays customers for cans, bottles, and cardboard. After processing these items, the center then resells them to XYZ Inc. The recycling center\u2019s payments to customers and the resale prices paid by XYZ Inc. are given in the table below.46. In 1 shipment, the recycling center sold a total of 2,700 cans and bottles to XYZ Inc. for $441.00. How many bottles were in the shipment?", "choices": {"A": "1,200", "B": "1,230", "C": "1,350", "D": "1,470", "E": "1,500"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "47. Given constants c, d, m, and n such that  x2 + mx + c  has factors of (x + 2) and (x + 4) and  x2 + nx + d  has factors of (x + 3) and (x + 7), what is mn ?", "choices": {"A": "16", "B": "18", "C": "29", "D": "60", "E": "168"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "48. For every angle \u03b8, measured in radians, which of the following is equal to sin(2\u03c0 + \u03b8) ?", "choices": {"A": "sin(-\u03c0 + \u03b8)", "B": "sin(\u03b8)", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": "sin(\u03c0 + \u03b8 )"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "49.  A small circle and a large circle are tangent at T, as shown in the \ufb01gure below. The center, 0, of the large circle lies on the small circle. The diameter of the large circle is 12cm. What is the ratio of the area of the small circle to the area of the large circle?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": "", "E": " "}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "50. For all positive values of a and b, which of the following expressions is equal to ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "51. The vector i represents 1 mile per hour east, and the vector j represents 1 mile per hour north. According to her GPS, at a particular instant, Tia is biking 30\u00b0 west of north at 16miles per hour. One of the following vectors represents Tia\u2019s velocity, in miles per hour, at that instant. Which one?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "52. Let and g(x) = x + 1 . Which of the following expressions defines ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "53. Consider sets A, B, C, and D such that B is a subset of A, C is a subset of B, and D is a subset of C. Whenever x is an element of B, x must be an element of:", "choices": {"A": "A", "B": "D", "C": "A and C ", "D": "C and D", "E": "A, C, and D"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "54. For all positive values of x, which of the following expressions is equivalent to ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "55. A company sells ice cream in 2-quart containers for $3.00 per container. The company also sells ice cream in 1.5-quart containers for $2.50 per container. What is the ratio of the price per quart for the 2-quart container to the price per quart for the 1.5-quart container?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "56. Each of 100 distinct playing cards is 1 of 5 solid colors and is numbered with 1 integer. There are 20 each of blue, red, yellow, green, and orange cards numbered 1-20. One of the 100 cards will be selected at random. What is the probability that the selected card will be blue OR numbered 17 ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "57. The changes in a city\u2019s population from one decade to the next decade for 3 consecutive decades were a 20% increase, a 30% increase, and a 20% decrease. About what percent was the increase in the city\u2019s population over the 3 decades?", "choices": {"A": "10%", "B": "20%", "C": "25%", "D": "30%", "E": "70%"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "58. Four golfers will be randomly split into 2 groups of 2 for a tournament. If Jill and Ramona are among the 4, what is the probability that they will be paired together?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "59. Jed is standing 10 meters from a maple tree that is 14 meters from a willow tree, as shown in the figure below, in which the measure of an angle is given. Which of the following equations, when solved for x, gives the distance, x meters, between Jed and the willow tree?(Note: For a triangle with sides of length a, b, and c that are opposite angles \u2220A\uff0c\u2220B, and \u2220C, respectively, c2 = a2 + b2 -2ab cos\u2220C )", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "60. Suppose the equations  and  are graphed in the same standard (x,y) coordinate plane. How many points of intersection do these graphs share?", "choices": {"A": "0", "B": "1", "C": "2", "D": "3", "E": "4"}, "correct": "A"}]}